‫All right, onto steps number three and four, so in step three, we need to create a nest module and
‫a controller.
‫I want to very quickly tell you what a module in a controller are so we're can take a look at a couple
‫of different diagrams.
‫All right.
‫So this diagram right here is probably going to look somewhat familiar if you've ever put together any
‫kind of server.
‫So in just about every HTP server you're ever going to create, you're going to have what is referred
‫to as a request response cycle.
‫Users are going to make requests to your server inside of your server, you're going to have some amount
‫of code that's going to process that request.
‫You might validate some data inside the request.
‫You might handle the request differently depending upon what route it is addressed to.
‫And then eventually you're going to formulate a response and send it back to ever made the request.
‫Now, just about every server you ever put together, this code right here that's going to process that
‫request is almost always going to look rather similar in nature.
‫In other words, this kind of request response cycle almost always has the same steps inside of it,
‫regardless of the language framework library or whatever else that you use to build your server.
‫So this code or that process almost always looks something like this.
‫So just about every server that you're ever going to put together is going to receive a request and
‫then might do some validation on data contained inside that request.
‫So, for example, we might validate some body or some data in the body.
‫The request we then might make sure that the user is authenticated or authorized to send us a request.
‫We're then going to route the request off to a particular function to handle the request that might
‫result in us running some particular business logic and eventually maybe access or store some information
‫inside of a database.
‫Then as a result of this entire process, we're going to formulate a response and send the response
‫back to whoever made us the request.
‫So, again, doesn't really matter what language, framework, anything that you're using, just about
‫every server is going to have the same series of steps.
‫In some cases, we might not be doing authentication, so maybe some steps will fall out.
‫But at the end of the day, this is kind of a very general case.
‫So in that case, we get special tools to help us address each of these very particular steps.
‫So in Nest, we have tools to help us create something called, say, a pipe pipes and just help us
‫validate data on incoming requests.
‫We also have tools that allow us to create something called guards.
‫Guards make sure that incoming requests are coming from users who are authenticated or authorized to
‫use our application.
‫We get also tools to create controllers.
‫Controllers contain routing logic.
‫We get tools to create something called services.
‫Those contain business logic and so on.
‫So throughout this course, as we work with Nest, we're going to learn about each of these different
‫sets of tools.
‫Each of these different sets of tools included in Nest are meant to help us and put together some piece
‫of handling incoming requests.
‫Besides just the five I'm showing right here, there's a couple of other tools we're going to look at.
‫So these are all tools inside of Nest that help us make things that handle these incoming requests.
‫So we still have controllers and services, which we saw in the last diagram.
‫We also have something called module's.
‫We have pipes, filters, guards', interceptors and repositories.
‫Again, we're going to learn about all these things throughout this course.
‫The absolute bare minimum that is required to put together the most simple nest application possible
‫is a module and a controller.
‫Every nest application you ever create is going to have at least one module and one controller inside
‫of it.
‫So in the diagram we were just looking at a moment ago, this one right here where we said we were going
‫to create a nest module and a controller.
‫These are the two things that are required to make the most simple basic app possible.
‫So that mind let's go back over to our editor and we're going to create a module and a controller.
‫So back over here to get started, I'm going to create a new directory called SIRC.
‫Then inside, there are going to make a new file called Main Dotty's.
‫May not.
‫This is going to be the first file that gets executed in any next project, so we'll usually have some
‫code inside of here to start up our application and start listening for traffic on the particular port.
‫Usually we will create a module and a controller in their own separate files, but right now we're going
‫to create the module and the controller directly inside the main text file.
‫So right now, all logic inside this file, but we will very, very quickly extract the stuff into separate
‫files.
‫To create a module and a controller, we're going to add in an important statement at the very top and
‫I'm going to import something called controller in module from at Negs Common.
‫So, like I mentioned, these are tools that Nesse provides to us to help us make a controller and make
‫a module.
‫To use them to create a controller, we're going to focus on the controller first, I'm going to create
‫a class called App Controller.
‫And then right above it, I'm going to add an at symbol controller and then call that like a function.
‫So this is referred to as a decorator in this case, this decorator is telling Nest that we are trying
‫to create a class that is going to serve as a controller inside of our application.
‫It is a class that is going to handle and root incoming requests.
‫Nest makes use of decorator's quite heavily, so throughout this course, we're going to have a big
‫focus on decorator's how they work and so on.
‫But for right now, we're going to have these decorators in and we'll discuss what they're really doing
‫for us later on.
‫Then inside of our class, we're going to add in a variety of different methods, each method is designed
‫to handle one kind of incoming request.
‫Specifically, we want to add in an additional method any time we want to have another route inside
‫of application.
‫So, for example, if we want to handle a get request to the root of our application, we might add
‫in a new method here called something like.
‫It root root.
‫Then whenever someone makes a request to our application, we want to route that request to this method
‫right here to do so, we're going to import another helper from the common library.
‫This helper is called the Gift Decorator.
‫This allows us to create route handlers that respond to incoming requests that have an HTTP method of
‫get to write about my method.
‫I'm going to put in at git like so.
‫And inside my method, any time someone makes a request to our roots that's going to run this method
‫right here and then all we have to do to respond to that request is return of value from this method.
‫So in this case, I can return simply a string of.
‫Hi there.
‫Now, in theory, if someone makes a request for application, it will get routed to this method right
‫here, we're going to return that string and Northwest is going to automatically take that string and
‫send it back to whoever made the request.
‫All right, so a lot of talking here, a lot of stuff going on, let's take a pause very, very quickly.
‫Come back in just a moment and start to create our module.
‫Leslie, want to mention is that these decorator's and things are really confusing right now.
‫Don't sweat it.
‫As I mentioned, we're going to be going over decorator's a tremendous amount inside this course.