‫Hello and welcome.
‫My name is Steven Grider, and in this course, I'm going to teach you everything I know about SJS before
‫we get started.
‫However, just a couple of very quick notes.
‫I want to go over specifically how you can get help if you ever get stuck as you working through this
‫course.
‫So if you get stuck at any point in time, the best place to go for help is that you'd make a discussion
‫board.
‫I have one or two teachers who watched the discussion in this course.
‫And if you ever have a question, just post your question and hopefully one, those ideas will be able
‫to answer your question.
‫If you do not get help there, you can always check out my Dischord server.
‫Discord is a kind of chat application.
‫If you want to join my Dischord server, you can find a link to it in the next lecture.
‫So the video right after this one.
‫And then finally, last way to get help.
‫You can always direct message me on me.
‫OK, so now you've got this little bit of administrative stuff out of the way, let's dive into the
‫world of Nest in the next video.