‫In between the last video and this one, I opened up my code editor inside my scratch project directory
‫so I can see that I've got my packages on file, which we just generated, and then all my dependencies
‫are inside that node modules directory.
‫Let's open up our packages on file inside of you.
‫We've got the dependency section and there's all the dependencies we just installed.
‫Now, believe it or not, we can actually understand a little bit around just by taking a look at these
‫dependencies and just understand what they do for us.
‫So very quickly, what are all these things about?
‫All right, so I took that section, put it in this diagram right here.
‫And we're going to take a look at four of these different dependencies.
‫The first one on that list is Nest James Common.
‫The Nest library itself is split out into several different packages.
‫The vast majority of functions, classes and whatnot that we're going to use to build a nest application
‫are coming from the common package.
‫So we're going to be importing that package quite a bit throughout this entire course.
‫Next up, we're going to skip over the core one and go to Platform Dasch Express, this one is a little
‫bit more interesting, and this is what is going to start to really help us understand what Nest is
‫doing internally.
‫So internally, Nest itself does not handle incoming requests.
‫Instead, here's a quick diagram of what's going on behind the scenes.
‫Nest relies upon some outside implementation to handle requests for it.
‫So inside of our nest server that you and I are going to eventually create, we are going to have some
‫place inside of our code where we have to plug in some kind of HTP implementation.
‫We have to provide some kind of server that says here is something that's going to handle incoming requests
‫and then eventually respond to them with an outgoing response.
‫In the world of Nest, we currently have two options for HTTP server implementations, we can either
‫make use of the very popular Library Express G.S. or another one called Fast Wi-Fi.
‫So we need to make a choice between both of these HTTP server implementations and essentially drop one
‫in for Nest to use.
‫Right now, the default is to make use of xpress, so if you ever generate a new nest project right
‫now as it stands, you are going to get express by default.
‫But we can easily say, you know what, instead of using Express, I want to use force to fly instead,
‫which is just another HTTP server implementation.
‫Now, as to why you would use one or the other, it comes down to the kind of application you are building
‫for you and I.
‫Inside this course, we're going to stick with the default of Express.
‫So this dependency that we have right here of Platform Dash Express says that we want to install an
‫adapter between Xpress and Nest, it's going to make the two of them work together.
‫And behind the scenes, Nest is going to use Express for handling all incoming HTTP requests.
‫All right.
‫Now onto our next dependancy reflect metadata.
‫This is a library tied to decorator's if you're not familiar decorator's, don't sweat it.
‫We're going to go into more detail on decorator's in just a moment.
‫And then finally, our last dependancy there is TypeScript.
‫So usually we write nest applications with typescript.
‫That is not strictly required.
‫You can write nest apps with JavaScript, but by far the most popular way to do this and probably what
‫you're going to see on any job or series project you work on is the use of typescript with Nest.
‫So we are installing the typescript compiler here.
‫All right.
‫Now back on track, let's continue with our application, we still haven't really said what this app
‫is going to do, but right now, let's just continue doing a little bit of setup and we'll eventually
‫decide on what kind of application we want to build in just a moment.
‫So at this point in time, we have installed dependencies.
‫The next thing we're going to do is set up a typescript compiler config file.
‫So this is going to be a classic test configuration file.
‫We're going to write out a couple of settings inside of it just to tell typescript how to compile our
‫project.
‫And usually we do not have to do steps one and two if we are using the next Seelie to generate our project
‫for us.
‫So these are just steps that we are doing because we are setting up our project from scratch.
‫All right.
‫So let's go create our config file and set up our typescript compiler very quickly.
‫So back inside my editor, I'm going to create a test config, JSON file.
‫I'm going to put in a set of curly braces, a string of compiler options.
‫And then I'll sign to that in object.
‫We'll put in there a couple of different key value pairs, the first one is module.
‫Of Common, James.
‫Then a target of its seventeen.
‫And then experimental decorator's of true and finally imit decorator metadata of true, once again,
‫I got to encourage you to double check your spelling on each of these words.
‫There's some tricky words inside of your make sure you've got the same spelling as I also make sure
‫you've got the same capitalization as well.
‫So decorator's should be capitalized, decorator's should be capitalized, metadata should be capitalized
‫as well.
‫So once again, these are just a couple of settings to get TypeScript to properly transpired our project
‫into normal JavaScript code before we eventually run it.
‫The two settings that are very relevant for us and we're going to learn a lot more about very quickly
‫our experimental decorator's and imit decorator metadata.
‫So we are going to come back to this file and go into more detail on what those are all about.
‫These two features right here, believe it or not, are at the absolute core of what makes Nest really
‫work.
‫So it's super important for us to understand those two settings.
‫All right, so that's step number two.
‫Let's take one more pause right here and then go through step number three and four in just a moment.